Finding Aid for Michel Oksenberg papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Academic and Professional Files (mainly correspondence)
  - 1977-1991
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1980-1990 (Box 24)
    - The National Interest (journal), 1986-1989 (Box 24)
    - National Security Council, 1981-1989 (Box 24)
    - New York Times, 1982-1990 (Box 24)
    - Newsweek magazine, 1988-1991 (Box 24)
    - Northrop Corp., 1985-1988 (Box 24)
    - Pacific Affairs (journal), 1985-1990 (Box 24)
    - Pacific Basin Institute, 1987-1990 (Box 24)
    - Pew Initiative in Diplomatic Training, 1988-1990 (Box 24)
    - Prentice Hall, Inc., 1977-1988 (Box 24)
    - Princeton University Press, 1981-1991 (Box 24)
    - Publications by M.E. Sharpe, Inc., 1980-1991 (Box 24)
    - Rock Creek Research, 1985-1987 (Box 24)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1980-1989 (Box 24)
    - School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS), 1980-1989 (Box 24)
    - Science Books International, Inc., 1981-1982 (Box 24)
    - Shanghai Consulate General, 1979 (Box 24)
    - Sidwell Friends School, 1982-1990 (Box 24)
    - Social Science Research Council (SSRC)
      - Council on International Peace and Cooperation (CIPS), 1987-1991; 4 folders (Box 24)
      - MacArthur Foundation, 1987-1989 (Box 24)
    - SOHIO (Standard Oil Co. of Ohio), 1985-1986 (Box 24)
    - Soong Ching Ling Foundation, 1988-1989 (Box 25)
    - SRI International, 1980-1982 (Box 25)
    - Stanford University, 1980-1984 (Box 25)
    - Stanford University Press, 1987-1988 (Box 25)
    - Swarthmore College, 1979-1989 (Box 25)
    - Taiwan, 1988-1990 (Box 25)
    - Taiwan Program at UM, 1989-1991 (Box 25)
    - Texaco, 1985 (Box 25)
    - The Trilateral Commission, 1981-1991 (Box 25)
    - United Board for Christian Education in China, 1983 (Box 25)
    - US Embassy Beijing, 1981-1989 (Box 25)
    - US Information Agency, 1987-1991 (Box 25)
    - Universities Service Centre, 1978-1990 (Box 25)
    - University of California Press, 1985-1989 (Box 25)
    - The University of Pennsylvania Press, 1985 (Box 25)
    - University of Washington, 1986-1990 (Box 25)
    - University of Washington Press, 1985-1989 (Box 25)
    - University of Wisconsin-River Falls, 1985-1987 (Box 25)
    - West Point, 1986-1990 (Box 25)
    - Westview Press, 1980-1989 (Box 25)
    - Wingspread China Studies Conferences, 1985-1991 (Box 25)
    - The Woodrow Wilson Center, 1982-1991 (Box 25)
    - World Bank, 1980-1991 (Box 25)
    - World Politics (journal), 1985 (Box 25)
    - Yale University, 1980-1988 (Box 25)
  - 1974-1991
    (Organizations files)
    - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS)
      - Correspondence, 1980-1986; 2 folders (Box 38)
      - Summer Language Grant Applications, 1986 (Box 38)
    - The Asia Society
      - China Council, 1981-1985; 4 folders (Box 38)
      - Correspondence, 1977-1990; 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Association for Asia Studies, Inc. (AAS) Correspondence, 1974-1989; 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Atlantic Council Correspondence and Memoranda, 1981-1986 (Box 38)
    - Brookings-Chinese Academy of Social Sciences Conference, 1981 (Box 38)
    - Burroughs Asia Ltd. Strategic Plan, 1982 (Box 38)
    - China Advisory Group (CAG)
      - Confidential Studies, 1980-1981 (Box 38)
      - Memoranda and Correspondence, 1980-1984; 4 folders (Box 38)
      - Update on CAG Clients, 1980 (Box 38)
    - Cincinnati Council on World Affairs, 1980-1982 (Box 38)
    - Committee on Advanced Study in China (CASC)
      - Applicant Evaluations, 1987 (Box 38)
      - Correspondence and Research Proposal Evaluations, 1987-1988 (Box 38)
    - Committee on International Relations Studies with the Peoples Republic of China (CIRSPRC), 1983-1988; 3 folders (Box 39)
    - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (CSCPRC)
      - 1980-1982
        - China Trip Report, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 39)
        - Committee Meeting, February, 1981 (Box 39)
        - Memoranda and Minutes, 1981-1982; 2 folders (Box 39)
        - Program, 1981-1982 (Box 39)
      - 1982-1985
        - Beijing Office Planning Committee Meeting, 1984 (Box 39)
        - Briefing Books, circa 1982; 1984 (Box 39)
        - Cable Traffic with American Embassy Beijing, 1983-1984 (Box 39)
        - Committee on Advanced Study in China (CASC), 1983-1985; 2 folders
          - Applicant Assessments, 1984 (Box 39)
        - China Trip Briefing Book, 1985 (Box 39)
        - Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 39)
        - Correspondence and Reports on PRC Experiences, 1983-1985; 3 folders (Box 39)
        - Grant Applications, 1983-1985; 10 folders (Box 40)
        - Meeting Agenda Books, 1982-1984; 4 volumes (Box 40)
        - Meeting Agenda Books, 1984-1985; 2 volumes (Box 41)
        - National Program for Advanced Study and Research in China, 1984 (Box 41)
      - 1985-1986
        - Committee on Advanced Study in China (CASC), 1985-1986 (Box 41)
        - Correspondence and Memoranda (2 journals), 1985-1986 (Box 41)
        - Memoranda and Minutes, 1985-1986 (Box 41)
      - 1986-1988
        - Correspondence and Memos, 1986-1987; 2 folders (Box 41)
        - Correspondence and Minutes, 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 41)
        - Grant Application Assessment Sheets, 1986 (Box 41)
        - Grant Applications, A-N, 1986; 3 folders (Box 41)
        - Grant Applications, O-Y, 1986; 3 folders (Box 42)
        - Meeting in China: Briefing Book, 1988 (Box 42)
        - National Program Selection Committee, 1986 (Box 42)
        - Rating Forms and Applicant Lists, 1986 (Box 42)
      - 1988-1991
        - CSCPRC (Zouping Project), 1988-1991; 4 folders (Box 42)
        - Memoranda and Reports, 1989-1991; 2 folders (Box 42)
        - National Academy of Sciences Meeting, 1990 (Box 42)
        - Paper: "Impressions of Zouping County", 1988 (Box 42)
        - Washington, DC Meeting, 1989 (Box 42)
        - Zouping Project Wingspread Conference, 1989 (Box 42)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1980-1987; 4 folders (Box 42)
    - Ditcheley Conference, 1985 (Box 42)
    - Joint Committee on Contemporary China (JCCC)
      - 1977-1981
        - Background Material, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 43)
        - Correspondence and Papers, 1980-1981; 3 folders (Box 43)
        - Information from Sophie Sa, 1980 (Box 43)
        - Luce Foundation, 1977-1981 (Box 43)
        - Meetings, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 43)
        - Meetings, 1981; 2 folders (Box 43)
      - 1981-1986
        - Correspondence, 1981-1984; 2 folders (Box 43)
        - Meeting Agenda Book, 1981 (Box 43)
        - Meeting Minutes and Reports, 1981 (Box 43)
    - Joint Committee on Chinese Studies (JCCS)
      - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 43)
      - Meetings and Grant Applications, 1982-1985; 3 folders (Box 43)
      - Meetings with American Council of Learned Societies, 1981-1982 (Box 44)
      - Reform Conference Papers, 1985-1986 (Box 44)
      - Summer Language Grant Applications, 1984 (Box 44)
    - National Academy of Science (NAS) China Trip (1 folder; 2 briefing books), 1984 (Box 44)
    - National Committee on US-China Relations (NCUSCR)
      - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1980-1983; 3 folders; 1 agenda book (Box 44)
      - Correspondence and Reports, 1983-1989; 3 folders; 1 agenda book (Box 44)
    - National Council for United States-China Trade, 1980 (Box 44)
    - National Science Foundation (NSF) Chongqing Conference, 1984 (Box 44)
    - Rand Corporation, 1980-1985 (Box 44)
    - Rockefeller Conference on Science in China, 1984 (Box 44)
    - Social Science Research Council (SSRC)
      - China Trip, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 44)
      - Correspondence and Papers, 1980-1987; 4 folders (Box 44)
      - Correspondence and Papers, 1978-1988 (Box 45)
      - Grant Applications, 1981; 2 folders (Box 45)
    - Trilateral Commission-China Trip
      - Biographies and Speeches, 1981; 2 folders (Box 45)
      - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 45)
      - Tokyo, 1979 (Box 45)
    - United States-China People's Friendship Association, 1981 (Box 45)
    - United Nations Association of United States of America, 1979 (Box 45)
  - 1992-1995
    (People/Organizations Files)
    - A-F (Box 49)
    - G-R (Box 50)
    - R-Z (Box 51)
  - 1995-1999
    (Organizations Files)
    - A-C (Box 52)
    - C-N (Box 53)
    - N-Z (Box 54)
  - (People Files) (includes some earlier correspondence), 1995-2001
    - 1995-1997 (Box 55)
    - 1998 (Box 56)
    - A-M, 1999-2001 (Box 57)
    - N-Z, 1999-2001 (Box 58)
    - 4 files of earlier materials to be interfiled (Box 58)
- Publications Files
  The Publications series consists of published articles, conference papers, or other presentations authored (or co-authored) by Oksenberg or containing references to him. Also included are newspaper articles quoting him or op-ed pieces written by him.
  - Bibliography of Oksenberg publications, 1965-1976 (Box 14)
  - "Agricultural Production, APC Autonomy and Administrative Change: China, 1955-1958" revised first draft of Master's Degree essay, undated (Box 14)
  - Asian Seminar at Columbia University; includes publication entitled, "Local Government and Politics in China, 1955-1958", May, 1966 (Box 14)
  - Asian Survey (monthly publication by the Institute of International Studies) articles and notes by MCO
    - 1966 (Box 14)
    - 1967 (Box 14)
  - Chinese citizenry; evaluation of individuals, apparently carried out by Oksenberg during trip to China, undated (Box 14)
  - Chinese Revolution, "The Leader and the Commissar: The Chinese Political System in the Last Days of the Revolution" (comments by Michel Oksenberg on John Wilson Lewis paper), 1967 (Box 14)
  - Current Scene article by Oksenberg on Second Echelon positions in China in 1955, 1965 (August 1965) (Box 14)
  - Dean's paper (?) Article by Oksenberg on local politics in China, 1955-1958 (Box 14)
  - Encyclopedia Americana Article analyzing the political system of Communist China, circa 1966 (Box 14)
  - Far Eastern Economic Review (FEER) Article on changes of political posts in the Chinese political hierarchy, 1965 (Box 14)
  - "Getting Ahead and Along in Communist China: The Ladder of Success on the Eve of the Revolution" (article prepared for the compendium volume on the Chinese Communist Party, December 1968 (Box 14)
  - "The Role of Ideology in the Formation of China's 1957-1958 Water Policy" (paper read at the 1967 meeting of the American Political Science Association), 1957-1967 (Box 14)
  - "Local Leaders in Rural China, 1962-1965" (revised paper prepared for the Joint Committee on Contemporary China, 1968) (Box 14)
  - Local Leadership (aggregated data) (Box 14)
  - Mass Irrigation Campaign (article, undated), 1957-1958 (Box 14)
  - Methodology paper and comments (prepared for the Joint Committee on Contemporary China, 1967) (Box 14)
  - New Hampshire Conference paper and comments on local leaders in China, 1967 (Box 14)
  - Occupational Groups
    - "Chinese Politics and the Configuration of Power and Influence Among Occupational Groups,", undated (Box 14)
    - "Occupational Groups in Chinese Society and the Cultural Revolution,", 1968 (Box 14)
  - "Policy Making Under Mao 1949-1968 An Overview" undated (Box 14)
  - Problems of Communism (joint article with Steven Goldstein on China's political spectrum, April 1974) (Box 14)
  - Shurmann, Franz (New York Times review by Oksenberg on Schurmann's book Ideology and Organization in Communist China, 1966) (Box 14)
  - Book Reviews and Magazine Articles, 1962-1968; 5 folders (Box 14)
  - Newspaper articles (primarily New York Times)
    - 1963, 2 folders (Box 15)
      (French and Belgian newspapers)
    - 1964, 4 folders (Box 15)
    - 1966, 4 folders (Box 15)
    - 1967, 8 folders (Box 15)
    - 1968, 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Publications, other writings, articles about or quoting MO
    - 1966-1982 (Box 59)
    - 1982-1987 (Box 60)
    - 1988-1994 (Box 61)
    - 1994-1998 (Box 62)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 63)
      (also includes articles about MO from his tenure with East-West Center; undated writings; drafts of writings; undated notes; etc.)
- Course Materials
  The Course Materials series includes syllabi, test questions, and some lecture notes from Oksenberg's classes at Columbia, Stanford and the University of Michigan.
  - Columbia University
    - Colloquium on Chinese Politics, 1970-1971 (Box 25)
    - Colloquium on Revolutionary Politics, 1969 (Box 25)
    - Lecture Notes, circa 1967-1971 (Box 25)
    - Methodology-Sources of Information, 1967 (Box 25)
    - Reading Lists, 1969 (Box 25)
    - Syllabi and lecture Notes, 1968-1973 (Box 25)
  - Syllabi and Lecture Notes-Revolution and Chinese Politics (Columbia, Stanford and UM), 1967-1975 (Box 25)
  - University of Michigan
    - Chinese Political System Graduate Seminar, 1973-1976; 3 folders (Box 26)
    - Course Promotions and Tests, 1975-1976 (Box 26)
    - Joint Seminar on Chinese Imperial Institutions, 1974 (Box 26)
    - Seminar on Chinese Politics, 1975-1976 (Box 26)
    - Course syllabi, 1980-1991 (Box 64)
- Student Files
  The Students series contains correspondence and students' coursework from the universities where Oksenberg taught.
  - Columbia University and UM, 1969-1977
    - A-Le (Box 26)
    - Li-Z (Box 27)
  - University of Michigan, 1976-1991
    - Bremmer, Paul, 1981 (Box 28)
    - Brown, Cheryl, 1978-1984 (Box 28)
    - Imai, Hiro, 1980-1984 (Box 28)
    - Jones, Eric A., 1977-1987 (Box 28)
    - Levitan, Bruce, 1980-1981 (Box 28)
    - Manion, Melanie, 1983-1989 (Box 28)
    - Mills, William, 1981-1982 (Box 28)
    - Oi, Jean C., 1976-1990; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Peng, Keyu, 1980-1981 (Box 28)
    - Perry, Elizabeth J., 1973-1976 (Box 28)
    - Rose, Robert, 1980-1982 (Box 28)
    - Rubinstein, Mitchell, 1981-1985 (Box 28)
    - Shambaugh, David, 1983-1991; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Stedman, Steve, 1980 (Box 28)
    - Walder, Andrew, 1980-1982 (Box 28)
    - Zweig, David, 1980-1983 (Box 28)
- University of Michigan
  The University of Michigan series includes correspondence with colleagues and administrators; files relating to student exchanges with China; files relating to general university activities including his interaction with individuals and constituencies with an interest in Chinese studies; and Center for Chinese Studies office files.
  - Correspondence with colleagues and administrators
    - Baker, Deane, 1989 (Box 28)
    - Barnes, Burton, 1986-1990 (Box 28)
    - Barnes, Samuel, 1981-1986 (Box 28)
    - Berkove, Lawrence I., 1981-1982 (Box 28)
    - Bryan, Keith, 1986-1990 (Box 28)
    - Bulkley, Jonathan W., 1986-1991 (Box 28)
    - Campbell, John, 1987-1991 (Box 28)
    - Chen Kan, 1980-1986 (Box 28)
    - D'Arms, John, 1987-1991 (Box 28)
    - Dernberger, Robert, 1981-1991 (Box 28)
    - DeWoskin, Kenneth, 1981-1991 (Box 28)
    - Diamond, Norma, 1985-1991 (Box 28)
    - Duderstadt, James, 1987-1991 (Box 28)
    - Eisendrath, Charles, 1980-1991 (Box 28)
    - Elman, Benjamin, 1985 (Box 28)
    - Feuerwerker, Albert and Yi-tsi, 1980-1991 (Box 28)
    - Fifield, Russell, 1983-1991 (Box 28)
    - Fleming, Robben, 1985-1988 (Box 28)
    - Forage, Paul, 1991 (Box 28)
    - Freedman, Ronald, 1985-1988 (Box 28)
    - Garver, John, 1983-1985 (Box 28)
    - Gitelman, Zvi, 1981-1986 (Box 28)
    - Goldenberg, Edie, 1989-1991 (Box 28)
    - Gordon, Roger, 1989 (Box 28)
    - Inglehart, Ron, 1981-1989 (Box 28)
    - Jackson, John E., 1985-1990 (Box 28)
    - Jacobson, Harold K., 1983-1991 (Box 28)
    - Jennings, Kent, 1987-1991 (Box 28)
    - Judge, Richard, 1985-1990 (Box 28)
    - Kincaid, William, 1986-1989 (Box 28)
    - Kingdon, John, 1986-1990 (Box 28)
    - Kish, Leslie, 1982-1989 (Box 28)
    - Lieberthal, Kenneth, 1973-1991; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Ma Wei-yi, 1985 (Box 29)
    - Mazrui, Ali A., 1989 (Box 29)
    - Meiland, Jack W., 1991 (Box 29)
    - Mills, Harriet C., 1980 (Box 29)
    - Moyers, Robert, 1989 (Box 29)
    - Munro, Donald, 1983-1991 (Box 29)
    - Osborn, June E., 1988 (Box 29)
    - Perkins, Bradford, 1987-1988 (Box 29)
    - Pierce, Roy, 1988-1991 (Box 29)
    - Rosenzweig, Robert, 1980 (Box 29)
    - Schwartz, Joel, 1984 (Box 29)
    - Shapiro, Harold, 1981-1987 (Box 29)
    - Singer, Daniel, 1985-1987 (Box 29)
    - Steiner, Peter, 1985-1986 (Box 29)
    - Stoltenberg, Clyde, 1989 (Box 29)
    - Swain, Mary Ann, 1985-1991 (Box 29)
    - Tanter, Raymond, 1989-1991 (Box 29)
    - Tichy, Noel, 1987-1988 (Box 29)
    - Ting, William, 1979-1982 (Box 29)
    - Vest, Charles, 1989-1990 (Box 29)
    - Walker, Jack, 1986-1990 (Box 29)
    - Whitman, Christina, 1980-1982 (Box 29)
    - Whyte, Martin, 1982-1990 (Box 29)
    - Wilson, Ernest J. III, 1983-1989 (Box 29)
    - Wilson, Linda, 1986-1989 (Box 29)
    - Woodcock, Leonard, 1980-1989 (Box 29)
    - Yeung Sai-cheung, 1977 (Box 29)
  - PRC Student Exchanges
    - Chinese Applicants to UM, 1984-1991; 3 folders (Box 29)
    - Chinese Medical Insurance, undated (Box 29)
    - Chinese Ministry of National Defense Foreign Affairs Bureau, 1989 (Box 29)
    - Chinese Students/ Scholars at UM, 1985 (Box 29)
    - Chinese Students/ Scholars Formerly at UM, 1982-1989 (Box 29)
    - Chinese Visitors and Acquaintances, 1981-1985 (Box 29)
    - Luce Scholars (Chinese) at UM Center for Chinese Studies, 1980-1985 (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous Chinese Correspondence, 1986-1990 (Box 29)
    - Other Foreign Applicants to UM, 1985-1989 (Box 29)
    - Presidents' Letter, 1983-1984 (Box 29)
    - UM-China Exchange Program (UMCEP), 1978-1991; 18 folders (Box 30)
  - Topical File
    - Asian Languages and Cultures Department, 1990 (Box 30)
    - Azazels, 1986-1992 (Box 30)
    - Center Directors, Inter-Center Council, 1990-1991 (Box 30)
    - Center for Chinese Studies, 1980-1992; 3 folders
      - Executive Committee Minutes, 1980-1991 (Box 30)
      - Publications, 1984-1986 (Box 30)
    - Center for International Business Education, 1990 (Box 30)
    - Center for Japanese Studies, 1983-1991 (Box 30)
    - China Coordinator, 1977-1984; 2 folders (Box 30)
    - College of Literature, Science and the Arts Administration, 1981-1985 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence with Chinese Students, 1981-1983 (Box 30)
    - East Asia Business Program, 1986-1991 (Box 30)
    - East Asian Initiative Advisory Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 31)
    - Ecumenical Campus Center, 1982-1989 (Box 31)
    - Global Leadership Program, 1988-1991; 3 folders (Box 31)
    - International Studies Advisory Committee, 1988-1990 (Box 31)
    - Korean Studies, 1984-1990 (Box 31)
    - Libraries, 1985-1991 (Box 31)
    - Michigan Summer Institute for Teachers of Asian Studies, 1986-1988 (Box 31)
    - Political Science Department, 1986-1991; 3 folders (Box 31)
    - Political Science Search Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 31)
    - President's Initiative Program, 1989 (Box 31)
    - Research Policies Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 31)
    - School of Business Administration Forum for Top Management, 1986 (Box 31)
    - Sichuan University Exchange, 1984-1985 (Box 31)
    - Study of US-China Auto Industry Cooperation, 1986-1987 (Box 31)
    - Task Force on Conflict of Interest and Commitment, 1983-1985 (Box 31)
    - Undergraduate Initiatives Fund, 1987 (Box 31)
  - Center for Chinese Studies office files
    - Accounts, 1976-1977
      - #012404 Allen Whiting project (Box 13)
      - #013357 Research Guides to Red Guard Publications project (Box 13)
      - #014754 U.S.-Chinese Policy Process project (Box 13)
      - #300594 Chinese Studies Account (Box 13)
    - Budget Projections, 1976-1977 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 13)
    - Directories and Addresses (Box 13)
    - Ditto Masters (Box 13)
    - Employee
      - Forms and Information, 1976-1977 (Box 13)
      - Pay Sheets, 1975-1976; 3 folders (Box 13)
      - Records, 1976-1977; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Equipment (requisitions and correspondence concerning), 1974-1977 (Box 13)
    - Expenses, 1976
      - General file (Box 13)
      - Travel reimbursements
        - Due (Box 13)
        - Paid (Box 13)
    - Expenses, 1977 (Box 13)
    - Forms, various (Box 13)
    - Jobs, Center for Chinese Studies
      - Applications (Box 13)
      - Classification
        - Descriptions (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous addresses, etc. (Box 13)
    - Orders placed, for books, posters, etc., 1975-1977 (Box 13)
    - Petty Cash, 1976-1977 (Box 13)
    - Political Science Course #756, 1976 (Box 13)
    - Save Temporary; personal data, course and teacher lists, etc., 1976 (Box 13)
    - Subscriptions, 1970-1976 (Box 13)
    - Telephone Accounts, 1976
      - Closed (Box 13)
      - Open (Box 13)
    - Typists, 1975-1976 (Box 13)
    - Winkelman, Stanley, "An Evening with Stanley Winkelman," invitations to China Center faculty to attend speech, 1977 (Box 13)
    - Workshop on the Pursuit of Political Interest in China (organized by Michel Oksenberg and the Social Science Research Council) held at the University of Michigan, August 1977
      - General correspondence, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Joint Committee on Contemporary China proposal for conference (Box 13)
      - Picnic sign-up sheet and dinner preference (Box 13)
- Research and Other Projects
  The Research and Other Projects series includes files from a miscellanea of China-related activities. These include Oksenberg's interest in China and the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT), his study of the energy bureaucracy of China, and other U.S.-China r topics. The series contains transcripts and audiocassette tapes of interviews, correspondence, reports, journals and press clippings. Interview tapes and transcripts are of particular interest: there are transcripts of Oksenberg's extensive interviews with former US ambassador to the PRC Leonard Woodcock [box 35], and detailed interviews with Oksenberg about his role at the National Security Council [box 35]. This series also contains trip and interview journals from Oksenberg's many trips to China. Noteworthy are his notes from interviews with Chinese refugees conducted by Oksenberg in the 1960s and 1970s.
  - Democratic National Committee, Study Group (Box 12)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1974-1975 (Box 12)
  - Department of Political Science, University of Michigan
    - Executive meeting minutes and reports, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Ford Report
    - Paper on Chinese studies, funded by the Ford Foundation, 1974 (Box 12)
  - Joint Committee on Contemporary China, Social Science Research Council
    - Activities concerning meeting of October 11-13 (Box 12)
  - Rockefeller Commission on Critical Choices
    - Correspondence and papers written including articles by MCO, "China: The American Interest, The Domestic Scene, and the Critical Choices" (1975); and "The United States and China" (1976), 1974-1976 (Box 12)
  - Beida Political Science Project, 1988-1990; 4 folders (Box 31)
  - China and the GATT
    - Miscellaneous, 1986; 3 folders (Box 31)
    - International Law Institute Conference on China and the GATT, 1986 (Box 32)
    - Interviews by MO and others, 1986; 3 volumes (Box 32)
  - Chinese Energy Bureaucracy, with Kenneth Lieberthal
    - Bureau of Reclamation (US Department of the Interior), 1988 (Box 32)
    - Bureaucratic Politics and Chinese Energy Development Master Copy, 1989; 3 folders (Box 32)
    - Chase Seminar, 1985 (Box 32)
    - China Trip Notes, 1985 (Box 32)
    - China trip with Senator Jackson, 1983 (Box 32)
    - Correspondence and Interview Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 32)
    - Expense Reports, 1984 (Box 32)
    - Interview Tapes, circa 1984-1986; 21 audiocassettes; 3 audiocassettes microcassettes (Box 33)
    - Interview Transcripts, 1984; 4 folders (Box 33)
    - Interview with Ma Deqing (PRC Ministry of Coal), 1984 (Box 33)
    - Interviews with US Executives, 1984; 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Outline and Notes, 1984-1986 (Box 33)
    - Petroleum Paper, circa 1986 (Box 33)
    - Proposal Drafts, 1985 (Box 33)